covad.net 2004-12-07

# Covad - Legal Notices - Privacy Policy

## **Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is very important to us and we want to make your experience on the Internet as enjoyable and rewarding as possible. This Privacy Policy describes how Covad collects information from users of Covad services (the "Services") and visitors to Covad.com, how we use the information we collect and the choices you have concerning the collection and use of such information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. The effective date of this Privacy Policy is July 1, 2004. 

**Collection and Use of Information**   
Visitors to our website are asked to provide certain information when they attempt to pre-qualify for our Services, such as telephone number and address. In combination, your address and telephone number are the only way we can determine the type of DSL service and speed we can provide to you because DSL technology is distance-sensitive and dependent upon location. Users are also asked to provide certain information when they sign up for our Services such as name, address, telephone number, billing information (such as a credit card number) and email address. The personal information collected from a user during the registration process is used to manage each user's account (such as billing and collections), to complete the ordering process and to provide our Services. 

Covad may use this information to contact you in a variety of ways. We may send you offers through email, phone or regular mail for Covad products and services, or offers on behalf of selected affiliates. You may exercise your options to not receive any promotional marketing offers via email through the means provided in the email or by calling 888-64-COVAD. Customers will still receive administrative emails from Covad. Covad may also contact users to request additional information and feedback. In addition, Covad purchases services from third parties and may need to provide information to those third parties in order to provide Services. 

Covad may also automatically collect and analyze information regarding the use of Covad's services and web site activity. Information collected may include but is not limited to web site traffic volume, frequency of visits, type and time of transactions, type of browser and operating system. For example, we automatically record your IP address so we can establish a broad understanding of site traffic patterns. This information is logged to help diagnose technical problems, administer the site, and improve the quality and types of service delivered. Covad may also collect, track and analyze information that does not personally identify a user in aggregate form. This aggregate data will be used at Covad's discretion and may be shared with third parties, but with no personally identifiable information attached. 

Covad may employ companies and people to perform tasks on its behalf, and will need to share personal information with these third parties to do so. These third parties do not receive any right to use personal information beyond what is necessary to perform these tasks. Covad may release or exchange personal information if required to do so to comply with applicable law or to enforce its rights or agreements or prevent fraud or reduce credit risk. For more information, see our Special Cases section below. 

**Children's Privacy**  
We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Our customer agreements for the purchase of our DSL services require users to warrant that they are 18 or older. 

**Voluntary Surveys**   
We may periodically conduct both business and individual surveys. We encourage users to participate in these voluntary surveys because they provide us with important information that helps us to improve the types of services we offer and how we provide them to you. Your personal information and responses will remain confidential, even if the survey is conducted by a third-party. 

We may take the information we receive from individuals responding to our surveys and combine (or aggregate) it with the responses of other users to create broader, generic responses to the survey questions (such as gender, age, residence, industry sector, or other demographic information). We then use the aggregated information to improve the quality of our services to you, and to develop new services and products. 

**Special Cases**   
It is Covad's policy not to use or share the personal information in ways unrelated to the ones described above without also providing an opportunity to opt out or otherwise prohibit such unrelated uses. However, Covad may disclose personal information or information regarding use of the Services if, for any reason and in our sole discretion, we believe that it is reasonable to do so, including: to satisfy laws, regulations or other legal requests for such information; to disclose information that is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Acceptable Use Policy or other policies; to operate the Services properly; or to protect Covad, our Services, our employees or our users. 

**"Cookies" and "Beacons"**  
A "cookie" is a small data file that can be placed on your hard drive when you visit certain Web sites. Covad uses cookies to collect, store, and sometimes track information for statistical purposes to operate and improve the products and services we provide and to manage our network and property. Also, we use cookies to gather information about your preferences as you navigate through the site. This helps us tailor and improve the information we present to you, so you enjoy an exceptional customer experience every time you visit. If you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you can still access most of Covad's web site although you may not be able to complete certain activities. 

Covad may also use "beacons" or "clear gifs", which are small pieces of code, on an anonymous basis. These beacons may be included in outgoing email messages or in our web site or our SMART account manager. This helps Covad determine which emails have been seen and which pages within our websites and our SMART account manager have been visited. 

**Third Party Sites**  
Covad's web site may contain links to third party web sites not associated with Covad. Covad is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of such sites. Users will need to review the policy statements of these web sites to understand their privacy policies. 

**How to Access or Modify Your Information**   
Covad offers users the opportunity to access or modify most information provided during registration. The exception to this is a primary or default email address. To access or modify such information, visit www.covad.net. 

**Revisions to This Policy**   
Covad reserves the right to revise, amend, or modify this policy and our other policies and agreements at any time and in any manner. Any revision, amendment, or modification will be posted on our web site: www.covad.com.
